前情提要
Previously on Stargate: Atlantis...
放下武器
Lower your weapons.
我们带来了基因疗法
We've come up with a gene therapy.
成功了之后你们就可以像转基因土豆一样
We think we can make it so that you
不用再吸食人类
will never need
to feed on humans again.
你们怎么可以无耻到如此地步？
How did you do that?
你不会真的认为是我们干的吧？
Surely you don't think we did this?
那儿怎么回事啊？Caldwell跑哪儿去了？
What the hell's going on?
Where's Caldwell?
我们大家一起动手，把船给抢回来
We need everyone we can.
We're taking the ship back.
Todd让我们把她带回来，不用动手
Todd let us take her back
without a fight,
但他把我们锁在外面了，现在缩到一个302战机舱
but he's locked us out of the controls
and retreated to one of the 302 bays.
这就是他炸毁设施的方法，把我们当人肉炸弹砸过去
That's how he's going to destroy
the facility, by ramming us into it.
你准备干嘛？
What'd you do?
打开一个足够大的超空间窗口，要容得下我们两艘船
Opened up a hyperspace window
big enough for the both of us.
我们刚刚“穿越”了这行星
We just traveled through the planet.
他们还要多久才到，几分钟的事情
- How long till they get here?
- Just a matter of minutes.
准备好隐形了吗？全搞妥了
- Are we prepared to cloak the City?
- Yes, it's all set,
根据以往经验，个人认为护盾比隐形好
but for the record,
I still say the shield is a better idea.
因为，隐形后就没有任何防护了
Look, that cloak offers us
no protection whatsoever.
如果母舰直接跑到我们头顶上…… 这怎么可能？
- If that hive opens up on us...
- How could they do that?
他们需要知道我们的确切位置。不是吧？你真的以为他们不知道？
- They'd have to know our position.
- What, you're assuming they don't?
我们跟踪了他们好几天，他们肯定把船上的资料给弄走了
We've been tracking them for days!
They've got some inside information!
还是不要泄露我们的位置，直到确认安全为止
It's better not to confirm our location
until we know for sure.
没理由给他们个活靶子
No sense in giving them
an easy target to shoot at.
Sheppard上校，你那边怎么样了？
Colonel Sheppard,
what's your status?
发呆中…… 等下我一通知你就发射章鱼导弹
- Standing by.
- Be prepared to fire drones on my mark.
收到，到时候说声就行了
Copy that.
Just say the word.
同志们
Well,
我想我们尽量做好准备吧，开始隐形
I suppose we're as prepared
as we can be. Engage the cloak.
好的
All right.
OK，躲猫猫躲猫猫……
Okay. Cloak's engaged.
他们应该马上就到了
They should be here momentarily.
怎么啦？什么事都没有发生
- What's happening?
- Nothing.
他们只是呆在那儿。他们知不知道我们在这里啊？
- They're just sitting there.
- Do they know we're here?
等等，我刚收到一个消息。
Hang on.
I'm receiving a transmission.
好像是个文件。用台隔离的计算机把它读出来。
- It's a file of some kind.
- Pull it up on a firewalled computer.
上面说什么？什么都没有……一堆乱码……
- What's it say?
- It's nothing... a random bunch of...
等等。这是什么东东？
- Wait a second.
- What is it?
加密了的
It's encrypted.
和Daedalus号用的加密算法一样
Using the same kind of algorithm
we use on the Daedalus.
别开火……基因疗法开发……
Hold your fire...
Gene therapy developed...
Keller医生的...
怎么回事呀？我也不知道
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
貌似文件有点损毁了
Looks like
the file's corrupted somehow.
……最初的结果无法消除疾病……
... initial results unable
to counteract the disease...
救救我们
Help us.
这什么乱七八糟的？
What on Earth does that mean?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
第五季17集 感染
Season 5 Episode 17
Infection (v. 1.00)
你什么意思，你弄不明白？
What do you mean,
you didn't understand him?
文件损坏了，我们只能恢复一些零碎的片段。
The file was corrupted.
We were only able to catch a few words.
即便如此，我们也能猜出来貌似他在求我们去救他。
Though, from what we could tell,
it seemed like he was asking for help.
凭什么啊？
With what?
去搞Jennifer的基因疗法？
Something to do
with Jennifer's gene therapy?
我们曾经给了他个机会去测试疗法，他却把我们给卖了。
Well, we gave him a chance to test it.
He double-crossed us.
我的意见是把它给轰出来
I say we blow him out of the sky.
我不同意你的观点
I can't say I disagree with you.
虽然我也觉得怪异，他就这么摆在那里
Though I do find it odd
he would just show up here,
明知道我们会做出什么样的战术反应
knowing that would be our reaction.
还有就是为什么会玩发送文件？而不是直接用无线电喊话？
And why send a file?
Why not just radio us directly?
无论他到底想要什么，对他来说肯定很重要。
Whatever he wants,
it must be really important.
也许我们应该回应
Perhaps we should answer back.
告诉他我们没收好他的文件？
Tell him that we did not
receive the file properly?
这样我们就隐形不了啦
We might as well
just drop the cloak.
他们能根据无线电信号，追踪到我们的确切位置
They'll be able
to trace our radio signal.
不，我们可以用一艘Jumper来发送
No. We might be able
to do it from a Jumper.
跑到母船附近再和他们通信
Approach the hive cloaked,
and communicate with them from there.
但到时他们可以定位Jumper的确切位置
But then they would be able
to pinpoint the Jumper's exact location.
没错，但Jumper的机动性比这城市强多了。
Yes, but the Jumper's a lot more
maneuverable than the City.
我们不是第一次飞到Todd的门口了
This isn't the first time
we've flown up to Todd's doorstep.
有没有可能把视频处理得清晰一点？
Any chance
you could clean up that video?
把他的说话拼凑起来？不行啊，丢失太多数据了。
- Piece together what he's saying?
- No, there's too much data missing.
好吧，上校？
All right.
Colonel?
就来
On my way.
现在试试看……
Coming up on it now.
我是John Sheppard上校。
This is Colonel John Sheppard.
听到请回话
Please come in.
我们没有正确接收到你的视频传输。
We didn't receive
your video transmission correctly.
请回答。
Please respond.
他们听到了吗？
Are they getting this?
当然，他们应该听到了的。我的意思是，没理由他们……
Yeah, they should be.
I mean, there's no reason why they...
怎么回事？我搜不到任何生命迹象。
- What is it?
- I'm not picking up any life-signs.
什么？我想Rodney是对的。
- What?
- I believe Rodney is correct.
我也探测不到有幽灵存在
I have also not been able to detect
the presence of any Wraith.
我还以为是我们距离太远了呢，但这样就说的过去了
I thought it was because we were
too far, but this makes more sense.
是不是啊？
It does?
这船最好不是另一个现实跑过来的（平行宇宙？）
This better not be a ship
from another reality.
几天前我们就已经在盯着他们的行踪了，不记得了？
We've been tracking their approach
for a few days now, remember?
它不像另外一艘Daedalus那样，突然凭空蹦出来的
It didn't just pop into our space
like that other Daedalus did.
你知道当他们冬眠时我们的探测器是探测不到他们的
Look, we know that they don't show up
on our scans when they're hibernating.
这也许是个更符合逻辑的解释
I'd say that's probably
a more logical explanation.
所有人集体冬眠？
Hibernating.
All of them?
他们可以预先制定轨道，让船自己跑到这儿来
They could've pre-programmed the ship
to fly here on its own, enter orbit,
甚至还预先录了一段留言
even send a pre-recorded signal.
为什么啊？只有一个方法可以知道答案
- Why?
- There's only one way to find out.
我们接到一个信号，是Sheppard上校在加密频道上
We're receiving a signal. It's Colonel
Sheppard on a secure channel.
接入通话
Patch me in.
上面发生了什么事？
What's happening up there?
呃，幽灵使了个空城计
Well, the Wraith have thrown us
a little curve ball here.
没发现生命痕迹，我想他们都在冬眠
Got no life signs on board.
We think they're hibernating.
为什么捏？
Why do that?
这就是我们想要查清楚的，但必须要登船
That's what we'd like to find out,
but it means boarding the ship.
你确定没问题吧？如果是个陷阱怎么办？
Are you sure that's wise?
What if it's a trap?
呃，如果是真的，那实在很恶心，如果他们玩埋伏的话
Well, if it is, it's a pretty lousy one.
If they ambush us,
你仍可以在下面把他们打下来
you can still take 'em out
from down there.
牺牲你的性命？
Sacrificing your lives.
真荣幸你会认为Todd费了那么大周章来杀我
I'm flattered you think Todd
would go to so much trouble to kill me.
我认为如果能干掉一艘母舰
Look, taking out a hive ship
总是件好事，我们也不容易有这样的机会
is always a good idea,
but we did come all this way,
况且……还能弄点装备
and... got all dressed up.
好吧
All right.
还是没有他们的信号
No sign of 'em yet.
为什么我会觉得一艘空母舰
Why is it that I find empty Hives
比满是幽灵的母舰更让人毛骨悚然
even creepier than the ones
that are full of Wraith?
相信我，我们最好还是快点离开这里
Trust me, we're better off this way.
舰桥应该在上面
Bridge should be up here.
给我点时间……
All right, just...
give me a few seconds.
好的
All right.
看，我说的没错吧，他们都呆在冬眠舱里
Well, I was right.
They're all in their hibernation pods.
哪儿？船尾的一些屋子
- Where?
- There's chambers in the aft section.
最怪异的事情，就是……如果我没理解错的话……
The weird thing is, though,
if I'm reading this right,
他们没给自己设定起床闹钟
they haven't given themselves
a wake-up call.
你在说什么呀？
What?
通常情况下，他们会留一部小部分人醒着
The normal procedure
would be to leave crew members awake
来盯着冬眠舱的状态，到时间再把其他人弄醒
so that they could monitor the pods
and bring the others out when it's time,
现在既然他们全部进去了，按理说应该有某种自动装置
but since they all went in,
there'd be some kind of an automatic
或者设置定时关闭功能，但我一样都没发现
or timed shut-down protocol,
but I can't find one.
那么，如果我们不弄醒他们……
So if we do not wake them...
他们就永远醒不来了。听起来很爽啊~
- Then they never will.
- Sounds good to me.
你难道不觉得奇怪吗？Todd会把自己
Do you do not find it odd
that Todd would leave himself
和他的全体船员都交由我们发落？尤其是经过上次的事件之后？
and his entire crew to our mercy?
Especially after our last encounter?
可能他的智商没有你想象的那么高呢
Maybe he's not as smart
as you think he is.
这是什么？某种能量波动
- What was that?
- Some kind of power fluctuation.
读数显示某些次级系统故障
I'm reading minor malfunctions
in several of the ship's systems.
等等……
Hang on...
我拿到Todd的视频文件了，貌似未受损
I got Todd's video file.
Looks like it's intact.
我想它已经坏了。可能在传输时候搞坏的
- I thought it was corrupted.
- It must've happened in transmission,
通信系统的小差错
some glitch in the comm system.
原件，在这了，搞掂。让我看看
- The original, it's there. All right.
- Let's see it.
别开火，我们没有恶意
Hold your fire.
We mean you no harm.
在你们采取行动之前，让我先解释一下我们为什么会来这里
Allow me to explain our presence here before you take any action.
如果你们看到这个信息
If you are seeing this message,
意味着我们的船已经安全抵达Atlantis
my ship has arrived safely
at Atlantis.
我来是因为我和我的船员们
I'm coming to you because my crew
都受到了某种疾病的折磨
and I have been stricken with a disease...
是由Keller医生开发的基因疗法所引起的综合症
A complication to the gene therapy developed by Dr. Keller...
不是吧？我们都没给他……
- Wait a second. We didn't give 'em...
- ... I acquired some of the formulation
当我们占领Daedalus时，我们获取了一些公式
while my crew and I were occupying the Daedalus.
我承认
I admit,
我也想看看它是否可行
I wanted to see if it would actually work.
它确实管用
And it did.
最初的试验结果很不错
The initial results were nothing short of astonishing.
你们可以自己看
See for yourself.
我感到非常满意，于是决定给全体船员施用
I was so impressed, I decided to treat my entire crew.
那时候我们才开始发现问题
It was only then that we began to notice problems.
第一批试验的船员生病并且死去
The first group grew sick and died.
没多久，其余的人也开始生病
Before long, others began to get sick as well.
我们自身的免疫系统无法抵抗这种疾病
Our natural healing ability was unable to counteract the disease.
于是我不得不来这里
I have come here
作为最后希望
as a matter of last resort.
我意识到
I realize
上次我们是有点分歧
we have had our differences of late,
也许你们会不情愿帮忙……
and you may be reluctant to help us...
但请记住……
But remember this...
如果我们死了，我希望你们
If we die, any hope you may have
将来不要再使用这种治疗方案
of distributing this treatment in the future dies with us.
决定权在你们
The choice is yours.
现在我们知道怎么回事了
Now that we know what happened,
我们可以朝他们发射章鱼导弹，删除文件然后走人
we can just fire drones at 'em, and close the file and move on.
你说他用来吸食的手已经正常了……
You said his feeding hand was clean...
意味着治疗生效了，至少，有效了一小会儿
Which means the treatment worked, at least for a while.
然后就把他们给害死了，我不知道……
Then it started killing them, so I don't know
如果他们都想变成这样
if they're gonna line up for this one.
我们必须找出来哪儿出了问题
Which is why we need to find out exactly what went wrong.
我们要一点一滴地仔细检查母舰上的医疗数据
We need to examine every scrap of medical data on that Hive.
我们甚至要唤醒一些幽灵
We may even need to revive a few of the Wraith
这样Keller医生就可以进行完整的医疗评估
so Dr. Keller can perform a complete physical evaluation.
很抱歉，但IOA强烈要求
I'm sorry, but the IOA is strongly committed
开发这种基因疗法
to the development of this gene therapy.
这是他们唯一的一次达成一致意见
It's a thing they all agree on.
如果这方案实在是不可行，那也没办法，但他们要看到证据
If it's simply not workable, so be it, but they're going to want to see proof.
我说这方案超好，把幽灵都杀光光了，你还要怎么样？
I say it works fine. It kills Wraith. What more do you want?
你是说我们把方程式保持原样
You're suggesting we keep the formula as is,
并且找个方法故意让它泄露出去？
and find a way of exposing them involuntarily.
为什么不？
Why not?
把幽灵一次性消灭光光，IOA肯定会高兴得不行
Get rid of the Wraith once and for all. The IOA would approved that.
问题在于传递渠道
The problem is in the delivery systems.
我们刚朝Beckett医生的逆转录酶病毒这方向努力
We just went down this road with Beckett's retrovirus.
就算我们成功把它改造为生化武器
And even if we do succeed in weaponizing the treatment,
也不见得我们能够成功全部灭绝幽灵
it is unlikely that we would wipe out the Wraith entirely.
最多我们可以削弱他们
At best, we would weaken them.
这我没有异议。另一方面，
- I don't have a problem with that.
- On the other hand,
如果我们可以成功地改造他们的进食习惯
if we do succeed in eliminating their need to feed,
也许就可以说服他们自愿接受治疗
we might be able convince them to take the treatment willingly.
这两个方面，无论是改进医疗方法或者把它变成生化武器
Either way, whether it's perfecting the formula as a treatment or a weapon,
我们都需要尽可能地收集各种资料
we need to gather as much information as we possibly can,
这又回到原点了
which brings me back to the same conclusion...
我们需要回到母舰上
We need to go back up there.
这次，Keller医生会和你们一起去
This time, have Dr. Keller accompany you,
还有Lorne少校的队伍，以及另外一个海军陆战队小组
as well as Major Lorne's team and another unit of Marines.
你仍然不能确定这是不是一个圈套？
Are you still not sure if it's a trap?
这么说吧，跟Todd打交道过程中
Let's just say I've learned to exercise
我学会了小心谨慎
an abundance of caution when dealing with Todd.
好吧
All right.
我的手下已经建立了环防圈，他们每小时都会检查
My men have established a perimeter. They'll be checking in every hour.
我知道！我知道！能量波动
I know! I know! Power fluctuations.
看，就像我说的，船上的某些系统有点儿运作不正常
Look, it's like I said, some of the ship's systems are acting up a little.
你把它修好就是了。一会儿就好
- Well, get it fixed.
- Yeah, give me a few minutes.
Lorne少校，我是Williams上尉
Major Lorne, this is Lieutenant Williams.
请讲
Go ahead.
先生，你要我们汇报每件不寻常的事情？
Sir, you wanted us to report anything unusual?
是的，上尉，你有什么发现？
That's right, Lieutenant. What do you got?
是这样的，长官，我正站在这里观察，听到了一些噪声，然后……
Well, Sir, I was standing watch, and I heard a noise, and...
这墙开始融化了
The wall is melting.
什么？再说一遍？
Sorry? Come again?
等等……我想它停止了
Wait a minute... I think it stopped.
原地待命
Stand by.
Williams，回答
Williams, come in.
上尉，请回话
Lieutenant, please respond.
你好吗？
How you doing?
一切都好？
That good?
我不知道，我想，我……
I don't know, I mean, I...
我想我已经取得进展了
I guess I'm making progress.
我查出来是什么杀死了他们。你做到了？
- I found out what was killing them.
- You did?
治疗确实是按原计划进行了
The treatment worked exactly like it was supposed to...
消除了他们的手掌的吸食口，并且激活了他们的消化系统
It eliminated their feeding hands, it activated their digestive systems,
就像模拟时一样
just like it did in the simulation,
但是，很不幸，它还产生了一种
but, unfortunately, it also created
致命的类似癌症的疾病，同时在削弱他们的
a virulent cancer-like disease at the same time that it was weakening
免疫系统，就是这个要了他们的老命
their immune systems. That's what killed them.
那么，你还可以做点什么呢？
Well, is there anything you can do about it?
不知道，可能，应该可以……
I don't know. Maybe. It's possible.
什么？
What?
刚才突然感觉到对我来说太难了
I just feel like I'm in over my head.
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
我看着你，Sheppard上校，还有小组的其他人……
I look at you, and Colonel Sheppard, the rest of the team...
你们经常做出抉择
You guys are so used to making decisions
这些抉择会影响成千上万人的生活
that affect the lives of thousands,
甚至几百万人
and even millions of people.
我并不习惯掌握着这个星系平衡的命运
I'm not so used to having the fate of the galaxy hang in the balance.
额，这个……你最好还是慢慢适应吧，有助于培养极大的自我满足感
Oh, that. You get used to it. Helps to have a massive ego.
听着，我不太懂得幽灵的生理学
Look, I don't know much about Wraith physiology,
但我了解你
but I know you.
如果有人可以处理好这个问题，那就是你
And if anyone can make this work, you can.
那么……这儿就是已知他最后所处的位置了
Well... This is his last known position.
上校！我们在这边发现了一些东西！
Colonel! We got something over here!
没有开火痕迹
Hasn't been fired.
要不要我叫更多人来帮忙找他？
Should I call up for some more personnel to help track him down?
我有个更好的主意，Rodney？
No, I got a better idea. Rodney?
这船上的地图是否可以加入生命探测信号？
Are the ship's schematics loaded into the life-signs detector?
我们第一次来就装上了，怎么啦？好的，等一下我们会用到
- I did it when we first got here. Why?
- Well, we're gonna need 'em.
有什么发现？没，只有我们俩
- Anything?
- No, it's just us.
Ronon，Teyla，你们那边有什么发现？
Ronon, Teyla, anything on your end?
没有，上校
I'm afraid not, Colonel.
好的，保持联系
All right. Stay in touch.
这是什么鬼东西？
What the hell is this?
应该是个开放的通道
It's supposed to be an open corridor.
我看看。这里
- Let me see.
- Here.
Rodney?
你给我们的地图很搞啊
This schematic you gave us is a piece of crap.
你说什么？这儿有个死胡同，地图上没有的
- What are you talking about?
- A dead end that's not on the map.
不可能！
That's impossible!
听着，我正盯着这里看呢。你也听着，我不知道该怎么说
- Look, I'm staring at it right now.
- Look, I don't know what to tell you.
我直接从船上的数据库把地图下载回来的
I pulled that schematic directly from the ship's database.
好极了，我还要兜一圈回去
Great. We have to double back.
Sheppard上校，我是Teyla，请回答
Colonel Sheppard, this is Teyla, please respond.
请讲。我们发现Williams上尉了
- Go ahead.
- We found Lieutenant Williams.
我想他已经挂了
I'm afraid he's dead.
发生了什么事？他受到攻击
- What happened?
- He was attacked.
谁？
By who?
不知道
I don't know,
但无论是什么东西，它想吃了他
but whatever it was, it tried to eat him.
你的意思是吸食？
You mean feed on him?
不，我的意思是吃了他，用牙齿咬的，像个动物一样
No. I mean eat him. With teeth, like an animal.
什么？
What?
好吧……向总部报告，让他们派些人去搬回尸体
All right... Radio back, try to get somebody to pick up the body.
与此同时，我们必须查出来到底怎么……
In the meantime, we're gonna have to figure out who the hell...
等等。我看到了一些东西
Hang on. We got something.
回到我们的位置
Move back to our position.
长官？
Sir?
在里面
In here.
另一个死胡同
Another dead end.
这完全说不过去，信号明明在我们头上
Well, this doesn't make any sense. The signal's right on top of us.
没事吧你们？
Is everybody okay?
我想是的。这是什么东西？
- Yeah. I think so.
- What the hell is that?
一个没有面具的幽灵战士
A Wraith soldier without the mask.
我从来没有想过他们会取下他们的面具
I didn't think they ever took those things off.
没有吸食手，记得吗？那他们吃什么？
No feeding hand, remember? How else is he gonna eat?
噢，爽了，这下我们要和饥饿的幽灵斗了
Oh, great. So now we have to contend with starving Wraith
那帮家伙刚学会用牙齿
who are just learning to use their teeth?
都是我的错，是我把他们所知道的
This is my fault. I'm the one that took away
唯一的进食机制剥夺了
the only practical feeding mechanism they ever knew.
好吧，我承认这有点麻烦
All right, look, I admit that it's a little disturbing,
但他们之前也并不像是人类的好朋友
but it's not like they were man's best friend before.
只是同一样东西的另一个版本
Just a different version of the same thing.
问题是，他们如何出来？能量波动
- The question is, how did it get out?
- The power fluctuations.
看来影响比我原来想象的更广泛
They must be more widespread than I thought.
那会怎么样？
So?
那么，这肯定有某种安全机制
So, there must be a safety protocol of some kind.
当能量中断时，冬眠舱会自行关闭
When there's an interruption of the power, the pods shut down
然后就把里面的人给放出来。但你已经稳定它了
- and release their occupant.
- But you stabilized it.
对不对？我是说……其余的冬眠舱都没问题吧？
Right? I mean... All the other pods are fine?
可能吧
They might be.
我……事实上我一直没确定在哪儿出了问题，所以……
I'm... I never actually figured out what was wrong, so...
有没有办法判断是否有其他冬眠舱也受到了影响？
Is there any way to determine if any of the other pods have been compromised?
这个我也不知道。也许，我们可以走下去看看
Well, I don't know. Maybe. I suppose we could go down and look.
我有个更好的主意，我们离开这鬼地方吧。
I got a better idea. Let's get the hell out of here.
除非我已经整理完相关的资料
Except I haven't finished sorting through the relevant data.
我意思是IOA…… IOA来咬我啊？我们撤
- The IOA...
- The IOA can sue me. Let's go.
什么？我知道这是条路
- What?
- I know this is the way,
因为早上我们还从这儿进来，但现在看起来变了
because we came by here this morning, but this looks different.
大概是你的幻觉吧？
You're probably imagining it.
也许不是……
Or not.
这墙从哪儿来的？本来这没有的
Where did that wall come from?
It wasn't there.
这怎么可能？我不知道！
- How's that possible?
- I don't know!
我们要找到另外一条路出去
We need to figure out another way out of here.
OK……看来如果我们走回头一点点
Okay... It looks like if we go back the way we came a bit,
我们可以走到另外一条走廊，可以绕到另外一边
we should hook up with another corridor that loops around the other side.
前面带路。好的……
- Lead the way.
- All right, well...
就是这儿了
All right, this is it.
穿过这里，大约100米，我们就到了
Through here, about a hundred meters, and we are there.
天哪！
Oh, my God.
这个…… 这可不妙。还用你说？
- Oh, this... This is not good.
- You're telling me?
dart船舱在另外一面，这是唯一出去的路
The dart bay's on the other side. This is the only way out of here.
你是不是准备告诉我为什么有那么大一个洞
You wanna tell me how a giant hole
魔术般出现在船中间？
magically appears in the middle of a ship?
事实上，关于这个，我有个看法。你知道？
- Actually, I have a theory about that.
- You do?
你瞧，那些小差错，之前解释过的
Look, these glitches we've been experiencing,
他们并不受能源规则限制，他们发布在每个主系统
they ain't confined to power regulation. They're in every major system.
我会叫它们做“一堆小差错。”这可是一场大装修
I wouldn't call 'em "glitches." This is a major renovation.
我知道，但你想想看
I know, but think about it.
幽灵船是基于有机组织的，对不对？
The Wraith ships are basically organic, right?
我的意思是，它们可以根据定制自己长出来
I mean, they're capable of self-regeneration when they're damaged,
但并非只有船体可以这样
but not just the hull.
还包括内部结构
The same systems regulate internal structure as well,
那么当这个系统发生故障，其余部分……
so if those systems are malfunctioning along with the others...
你认为这艘船正在自我修复？
You think the ship is repairing itself incorrectly?
不是修复，更像重新构造
Not repairing so much as reconfiguring.
你想想，当Williams死之前他说看到墙壁正在融化
Look, before he was killed, Williams said he saw the wall melt.
我们也经历过了，那些死胡同，本来应该是走廊的
We've experienced it, dead ends when there's supposed to be corridors.
这些“重新构造”是不是已经把我们去dart船舱的路给封死了？
And this reconfiguration has completely cut us off from the dart bay?
我只能说，是的。和Atlantis通话
- From what I can tell, yes.
- Get on the line to Atlantis.
让他们派些Jumper和工程兵过来，我们要想办法出去了
Have some Jumpers and combat engineers. We need to get outta here.
事实上，我也没办法，因为通信系统
Actually, I can't do that, because the communications systems
已经完全离线
are now completely offline.
你丫…… 说吧，你要我干嘛？
- Rodney...
- Look, what do you want me to do?
如果我知道这是什么原因引起的，我还能想想办法
If I knew what causing this, I could do something about it,
但是这些故障，到处都是
but these malfunctions are showing up everywhere.
我的意思是，它们看上去完全是随机的
I mean, they seem to be entirely random!
那我们只好困在这儿了？目前来说，是的
- So we're stuck here?
- For the time being, yes.
我一点办法都没有了
I do have an idea.
我们唤醒Todd。什么？
- We revive Todd.
- What?
他了解这船，也许他能知道哪儿出了问题
He knows about this ship. Maybe he can help me figure out what's wrong.
你不会忘了上个幽灵跑出了吃了我们一个海军陆战队员吧？
You do remember the last Wraith that came out ate one of our marines?
他只是个幽灵战士
He was just a warrior drone.
我们长期以来都怀疑他们的大半生
We've long suspected they spend the majority of their life
都在其他幽灵的心灵控制之下
under the controlling mental influence of the other Wraith.
当你突然去掉心灵控制，发生这样子的事情一点不奇怪
It's not surprising if you remove that influence
他们回到野兽状态
they revert to an animal state.
但这种情况也可能发生在Todd身上。是的，但你忘了一件事情
- But that shouldn't happen with Todd.
- Yeah, but you're forgetting one thing.
我还没找到了一种可以治愈他们致命疾病的方法
I haven't found a cure for the disease that was killing them.
我的意思是，就算把他放出来，他也挺不了很久
I mean, we take him out, and he might not last long.
好吧，这是一项，但我更喜欢有个计划
Well, that's the one thing， I like about the plan.
好极了！
Oh, great!
导航系统正在启动，无论你有什么计划，都要快一点了。
Navigation's acting up. Whatever we decide, we gotta do it quickly,
因为我们在这种故障状态下坚持不了多久
because I cannot stay ahead of these malfunctions for much longer.
你确定要这么干吗？
You sure about this?
感觉怎么样？
How you feeling?
没想到你会来
I did not think you would come.
朋友是用来干吗的？（相互利用呗）
What are friends for?
你的船要烂了
Your ship is malfunctioning.
我们需要你来修一下
We need you to fix it.
你唤醒我就是为了这个？没错
- You woke me for this?
- That's right.
我们有活要干了
We've got work to do.
你知道，我已经……试过这个了
You know, I did...
I tried that already.
好吧，好吧，你继续，我只是飘过……
Okay, all right. You know what? You just go ahead.
今天早上有些人在冬眠舱另外一面醒来
Somebody woke up on the wrong side of the pod this morning.
这没道理
This makes no sense.
这系统不稳定。我已经告诉过你了！
- The systems are behaving erratically.
- I've been trying to tell you that!
你都干了些什么？什么都没干！
- What have you done to them?
- Nothing!
我们一上船就发现它已经这样抽风了
They've been acting screwy since the moment we came on board!
什么都失灵了
Nothing's responding the way it should.
就有点像……
It's almost as if...
像什么？
What?
不，这不可能
No, it's not possible.
什么不可能？
What's not possible?
我想我知道为什么这船会发生故障了
I believe I know why the ship is malfunctioning.
船感染了病毒？
The disease is in the ship?
这是唯一合理解释
It is the only explanation that makes sense.
既然你那么说
If you say so.
这怎么可能？
How is that even possible?
在冬眠的过程中
During the process of hibernation,
母舰和幽灵不断交换流质
there is a continuous exchange of fluid between Wraith and hive.
病毒肯定也是透过这种方式传播
The disease must have been transmitted in this manner.
晕倒，那我们现在在一个巨型肿瘤里面飞行了
Great. So we're flying around in a giant tumor.
而且还没有出口
With no way off.
时间拖得越久，病毒就发展得更凶猛
As time goes on and the disease progresses,
越来越多的系统会受到影响……
more and more systems will become affected...
惯性阻尼、生命支持系统、船体完整性……
Inertial dampeners, life support, hull integrity...
我们能不能让它着陆？
Can we land it?
在最好的状态下，让一艘母舰着陆都异常复杂
Landing a hive is a tricky proposition in the best of circumstances.
在这种状况下，我可不建议这样
Under these conditions, I would not recommend it.
那么我们还能怎么办？
So, what do we do?
我们只有一件事情可以做了
There is only one thing we can do.
我们必须治愈这种疾病。等一等
- We must cure this disease.
- Wait a second.
目前我也是仅仅从皮毛上知道在治疗过程中出了什么问题
I've barely scratched the surface on what went wrong here.
我的意思是，可能要花数月时间来分析那些数据
I mean, it could take months to analyze the data.
按照飞船目前这种退化速度
At the current level of the ship's degradation,
估计在它变得不适合居住之前，我们还有四天时间
I estimate we have four days before it becomes uninhabitable.
所以，你最好马上开工
Well, you better get to work.
现在怎么样了？Rodney？
How's it going, Rodney?
很超现实的，每次我修好某样东西
Aside from the fact, every time I fix something,
另外一样又坏了，好的很哪
something else breaks, fine.
那么我们会遇到越来越频繁的能量波动？
So we can expect more of these power fluctuations?
看来情况会变得更糟糕。那我们就有问题了
- Likely. Probably gonna get worse.
- Then we've got a problem.
其他的幽灵。我们可不能让他们都跑出来
- The other Wraith.
- We can't afford to let them get out.
还好，我已经识别出
Well, I have been able to identify
我们刚谈到的安全协议
that safety protocol I was talking about.
我也许可以重载它，但要做一点点关键性修改
I won't be able to override it, but I'll make a few key alterations.
额，像怎么样的？我的意思是，最简单的方法
- Yeah? Like what?
- Well, I mean, the simplest thing to do
当冬眠舱关闭时
would be to make it so the pods don't release the Wraith
可以让冬眠舱不再放幽灵出来，但是……
when they shut down, but...
这会杀了他们。通常是窒息而死
That would kill them.
Basically suffocate them.
好极了，他们是幽灵
Great. They're Wraith.
是吗？他们接受了治疗，他们不再吸食人类
Are they? They've taken the treatment, they no longer feed.
你去告诉Williams上尉吧。那Todd怎么办？
- Tell that to Lieutenant Williams.
- What about Todd?
如果他的船员大量死亡，他肯定想知道怎么回事
If significant numbers of his crew are killed, he will demand to know why.
只是另外一种故障引起的，开始吧
Just another malfunction. Do it.
好的
All right.
你没事吧？
You all right?
等一下就会过去了
It will pass.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没想到会变成这样
I never meant for any of this to happen.
我的确认为这种治疗对每个人都有好处
I honestly thought the treatment would make things better for everyone.
你觉得很搞笑吗？
What's funny?
我觉得很有意思
I find it amusing,
人类向幽灵道歉
human apologizing to Wraith.
你无法理解怜悯
You don't understand compassion.
你只是把它视为软弱
You just view it as a sign of weakness.
难道不是吗？
Isn't it?
不，差远了
No, not by a long shot.
我不敢担保Sheppard上校会同意你的观点
I'm not sure Colonel Sheppard would agree with you.
Sheppard上校是个战士，而我是个医生
Colonel Sheppard's a soldier. I'm a Doctor.
啊，对
Ah, yes.
他的本职是杀戮，而你的工作是拯救生命
His job is to take lives, and yours is to save them.
不，他的工作也包括拯救生命
No, his job is also to save lives.
他只是使用一套不同的工具
He just has a different set of tools.
好了……
All right...
我刚创建了一个子程序，来跳过安全协议
I've created a program
to override the safety protocol.
你确定我们要这么干吗？
You sure you want me to do this?
继续。好的
- Go ahead.
- All right.
这是什么？
What is that?
只是其中一间冬眠室，它不接受新的指令
It's one of the hibernation chambers. It's not accepting the new commands.
糟了，我在这里无法访问系统
No, it's no good. I can't access it from here.
有多少个幽灵在里面？
How many of them are in there?
这是其中比较小的一间，最多也就几十个吧
It's one of the smaller chambers, so a couple of dozen at the most.
我们要找其他的方法来对付这帮家伙了
We're gonna have to figure out another way to deal with these guys.
上校……
Colonel...
这可不是什么好兆头，赶紧行动
Well, that's not a good sign. Let's move.
能量波动
Power fluctuations.
更多幽灵会跑出来
More of them could be out.
这正是我担心的
This is what I was afraid of.
我刚知道你为什么不能访问最后一个冬眠室了
We just figured out why you weren't able to access the last chamber.
什么？什么原因？
What? What is it?
我们来晚了，冬眠舱已经打开了
We're too late. The pods are opened.
有多少跑了出来？
How many got out?
全部
All of them.
现在我们分成几个小组，把每层甲板分成四个区
Alright, we're gonna split into teams. Divide each deck into four sections,
我们要逐层清扫，从这个地方开始
we're gonna sweep through, starting from this position.
别犹豫
Don't take any chances.
看到移动物体就开火，都清楚了吗？
Shoot anything that moves. Everyone clear?
好的，开工吧
All right, let's move out.
在这里
It says here
在你的治疗方案里
you attempted to use Iratus DNA
你试图使用Iratus虫的DNA
in your treatment.
没错，我认为用Iratus虫纯净的基因
I thought using the pure DNA of an Iratus bug
也许有助于防止幽灵能力的衰退
would help prevent the deterioration of your Wraith abilities.
这是Michael的主意，不过可能说了你也不会相信
Got the idea from Michael, if you can believe that,
但是，很不幸，它没起作用，那么……
but, unfortunately, it didn't work, so...
怎么啦？
What is it?
我有个主意了
I have an idea.
Sheppard上校，请回答。我是Sheppard
- Colonel Sheppard, come in, please?
- This is Sheppard.
我要你下到实验室，Todd有话要跟你说
We need you to come down to the lab.
Todd needs to speak to you.
现在我有点忙，能不能等等？
I'm a little busy right now. Can it wait?
看来不行
Apparently not.
去跟Teyla和Ramirez汇合，直到我回来
Meet up with Teyla and Ramirez till I get back.
有什么事情急成这样啊？他说有个方法可以可以弥补
- What's so damn important?
- He says there's a way to fix this.
弥补什么？
Fix what?
治愈疾病？不是治愈
- Cure the disease?
- Not cure it,
而是恢复
but undo it.
到底什么意思啊？
What are you talking about?
你知道，健康的幽灵本来就有些特殊的能力
As you know, healthy Wraith have an inherent ability
比如我们从来不得慢性病
to heal themselves of almost any ailment,
但并非一开始就是这样，几十万年前
but this has not always been the case. Hundreds of thousands of years ago,
曾经有过一种把死幽灵当作活幽灵来医的方法
there was a treatment of last resort.
好吧，给我讲讲幽灵史
All right, spare me the history lessons.
一些病入膏肓的重症幽灵
A terminally ill Wraith
有时候可以神奇地恢复到最佳健康状态
could occasionally restore himself to perfect health
如果他让一条那种你们叫做“Iratus虫”
if he allowed an Iratus "bug", as you call them,
特别是虫后，来吸食他的话
specifically a queen, to feed on him.
你不会刚刚才想起这回事吧？
And you're just bringing this up now?
这种治疗方法早就废弃了，因为太危险
The process was abandoned long ago because it is dangerous,
几乎总会让尝试的幽灵送命
almost always resulting in the death of the Wraith in question.
我只是……
I only...
现在才考虑这个，是因为……
consider it now because...
看来我们……
it would appear that we are...
没什么希望了
beyond hope.
现在，这里有个行星
Now, there is a planet
不超过三天的路程，在那里我们能找到我们需要的东西
less than three days' journey where we will find what we need.
我们几乎不能让这一砣东西保持在轨道上，难道你想用它来超光速飞行？
We can barely keep this thing in orbit,
and you want to take it into hyperspace?
我应付得了
I can manage it.
还是算了吧，我看还是在这里找出一个解决方法比较靠谱
Well, forget about it. We're gonna
come up with a solution right here.
这是唯一能拯救我船员的方法。好吧，那我们不走
- This is the only way to save my crew.
- Well, we're not leaving.
至少出于礼貌，你也应该对我诚实点
At least do me the courtesy of being honest.
这跟你没关系，你也没什么理由
This is not about not you not wanting
冒险乘坐一艘受损的船进入超空间
to risk a jump to hyperspace on a damaged ship.
你不想我去，是因为我将要拯救上百个
You do not want me to go because I'll be restoring the lives
病得半死的幽灵，包括我自己
of hundreds of unhealthy Wraith, including myself.
我必须承认，这念头我也有过
I got to admit, that did cross my mind.
但这疾病你们有不可推卸的责任
This disease is your responsibility.
如果当初我不同意和你讨论这个……
If I had not agreed to meet with you to discuss this...
你们的“发明”
innovation of yours,
我和我的船员也不会处于如此境地
my crew and I would not be in this predicament!
这么说来，我是不是应该仁慈一点
Well, I might be feeling a little more charitable
上次我们决定彼此信任的时候
if you hadn't tried to kill half my people
如果你没有试图杀死我们一半的人！
last time we decided to trust each other!
你欠我的，Sheppard
You owe me this, Sheppard.
我什么都没欠你
I don't owe you anything.
把他带出去
Get him out of here.
看来，我也没法指望得到他的帮助了
Well, I guess I can't count on his help anymore.
这是什么？Sheppard，你要上来一下了
- What was that?
- Sheppard, you're gonna wanna get up.
继续努力
Keep working.
这是什么？
What the hell was that?
看来Todd对这艘船能挺多久的估算要有点折扣了
Looks like Todd's estimate of how long the ship's gonna last is a little off.
什么意思？还记得那个洞吗？它正在变大
- What are you talking about?
- Remember that hole? It's growing.
已经开始威胁船体的完整性了，但这还不是最严重的问题
It begins to threat the hull integrity, but that's not the biggest problem.
看到了没？
See that?
这是一条表示结构薄弱点的线，正好横跨整个船身宽度
That is a line of structural weakness right across the width of the hive.
如果这里稍微发生点爆炸，这船就会被撕成两半
If there's an explosive decompression, this thing could be ripped in half.
我是Sheppard，全体队员返回，立即返回
This is Sheppard, all teams fall back. Fall back immediately.
我们还没搞妥这些幽灵
We're not finished with the Wraith.
别管他们了，这船身快裂开了，赶紧离开
Just leave 'em. The hull's failing. Get the hell out of there.
你们听到了，赶紧走！
You heard the man. Let's move!
我们走！
Let's go!
赶紧跟上
Come on! Hurry up!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
我们离开这鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
怎么回事？
What is it?
门卡住了，怎么都开不了
The door's jammed. Won't open.
Rodney，我是Teyla，我们被困住了，这门怎么都打开不了
Rodney, this is Teyla. We are stuck behind a door that will not open.
你能不能帮忙？控制系统出故障了
- Can you help us?
- The controls are malfunctioning.
我看看能不能重载它，给我几分钟
I can't seem to override them. Just give me a minute.
我们可能没几分钟了，Rodney
We might not have a minute, Rodney.
你个香蕉苹果菠萝……
Crap.
啊？兄弟们，你们要马上离开那里
Uh, guys? You need to get out of there now.
听到了没有，马上离开！
You hear me? Get out of there now!
Sheppard！回答！快回答！
Sheppard! Come in! Please!
我们在这里。谢天谢地！
- Yeah, we're here.
- Oh, thank God.
那个隔离舱还能挺得住吗？是的，目前还行
- I take it the bulkhead held?
- Yeah, for now.
我把它密封了，这样就不会减压
I was able to seal off
so we won't depressurize,
但你们要下到这里来
but you need to get down here...
现在又怎么了？
What now?
这艘船把自己撕成开的时候，我们的轨道也发生了改变
The ship tearing itself apart, shifted our trajectory.
我们正一头朝行星栽下去！
We're headed straight for the planet!
我们的情况怎么样？
What's our status?
我认为用“失控”来形容比较恰切
I would say "screwed" is an apt description.
我们会不会烧起来？不，返回时没事
- Are we going to burn up?
- No, we're gonna survive re-entry.
事实上，它还会让我们变慢一点，但远远不够
In fact, it'll slow us down a little, but nowhere near enough.
你能不能把我们带到水上？无论陆地还是水面，在这个速度下
- Can you get us over the water?
- Land, water, at that speed
在撞击瞬间我们马上就被汽化了。我们要采取行动了
- we're going to be vaporized on impact.
- We've got to do something.
比如？想！
- Like what?
- Think!
我不知道……OK，就这么着吧
I don't know... Okay, right.
把机动推进器朝前，但它们都没有能量了
Forward maneuvering thrusters. But they're not getting any power
因为推进器的小导管已经给扯成了两半
because the propulsion conduits have been ripped in half.
我也许可以重新调整能量流向推进器，这样它就能减缓我们下坠的速度
I may be able to reroute power to them so they can slow our descent.
没问题，你说了算。但我根本不知道怎么搞！
- All right, now you're talking.
- I haven't a clue how to do it!
就算系统正常
Even if the systems were functioning,
也要花好几个小时来创建这样一个工作环境
it would take me hours to create that kind of work-around.
好吧，你继续干吧
All right, just keep working on it.
你又去哪儿？我去找帮手
- Where the hell are you going?
- I'm gonna go get some help.
起来。你就不能不惹我吗？
- Get up.
- You can't quite leave me be.
没时间跟你玩了
I don't have time to play games.
你知道为什么会那么晃吗？哦，我猜猜……
- You know what that shaking is?
- Oh, I can guess.
我们离开轨道了，正在冲入大气层
We've lost orbit. We're entering the atmosphere,
这意味着几分钟后，我们就会撞向行星
which means in a few minutes, we're gonna slam into that planet.
倒是可以死个痛快
A quick death will be a welcome reprieve.
我没想到你就是这个么有始无终的人
I didn't think you were such a quitter.
听着，你让这艘船安全降落，我就带你去虫虫星球
Look, you get this ship on the ground, I'll take you to your bug planet.
你希望我会相信你？
And you expect me to believe that?
我说话算数
My word.
包括我所有船员？
And my crew?
他们已经死了
They're dead.
这艘船裂成两半，整个船尾都没了
The ship sheared in two. We lost the entire rear section.
如果我们去那个行星，这一切就不会发生！
If we'd gone to the planet, none of this would have happened!
你永远到不了那里，你心知肚明！
We would have never made it there, you know it.
船身损坏太严重了
The hull was too damaged.
现在，我能理解你因为船员而火大
Now, I understand you're pissed off about your crew,
但我们正准备去和他们汇合，除非有人可以让我们慢下来
but we're about to join 'em, unless somebody manages to slow us down,
你还准备来帮忙吗？
so are you gonna help us out?
我们进入大气层了
We're in the atmosphere.
高度100,000英尺
Altitude 100,000 feet.
没用的，我没法控制它
It is no use. I cannot control it.
滚一边去！
Move aside!
你放心他吗？他又能拿我们怎么样？现在我们已经是自由落体了
- You sure about this?
- What can he do? We're in a free fall.
我想我能新建一条旁路来输送能量
I believe I can successfully create a bypass that will deliver power
到前面的机动推进器，但这样要花一点点时间
to the forward thrusters, but it will take a few moments.
慢慢来。15秒后撞击
- You just take your time.
- Impact in 15 seconds.
如果成功了就不会，推进器点火！
Not if I can help it.
Firing thrusters!
40,000英尺。仍然下坠太快了
40,000 feet. Still descending too fast.
还不够！与其在那里批评我
- It's not enough!
- Instead of criticizing,
你还不如去帮我多弄点能量！
perhaps you could work at getting me some more power!
就来！
I'm on it!
20,000英尺
20,000 feet.
调整推进器角度，让这船身水平
Angle the thrusters. Try to get the ship level.
这样能够让它漂过水面
We can fly her across the water.
相信我，我以前干过
Trust me. I've done this before.
10,000英尺。好了好了
- 10,000 feet.
- That's it.
我是我们能获取的所有能量了
That's all the power we've got.
2,000英尺！
2,000 feet!
我想说的就是这个！我们正在失去惯性阻尼！
This is it! We're about to lose inertial dampeners!
他们刚刚撞落水面，我取得坐标了
They just hit the water. I've got the coordinates.
马上把他们带回救生艇
Relay them to the rescue Jumpers immediately.
上校，很高兴看到你康复
Colonel. Good to see you back on your feet.
你的其余队员怎么样了？你知道的，正在康复中
- How's the rest of your team?
- You know, recovering.
当撞击水面的时候，我们受到了巨大冲击
We took quite a jolt when we hit the water.
可以想象得出
I can imagine.
你很幸运
You were lucky.
那时候Kersey少校
By the time Major Kersey
费了九牛二虎之力打通一条通道去到你的位置
was able to blast his way down to your position,
那个母舰，那些剩余部分，有一半已经灌满了水
the hive, what remained of it, was already half full of water.
把你捞起来后过不了几分钟它就沉了
It sank minutes after they extracted you.
真希望能醒着看到这一幕
Wish I was awake to see that.
他怎么样了？不太好
- How is he?
- Not well.
他拒绝任何治疗
He hasn't responded to any treatment.
我接到你的申请
I received your request.
怎么样？
And?
如果说错了请原谅
Forgive me if I'm wrong,
当初刚看到那艘船时，你不是想炸掉它吗？
but weren't you the one who wanted to destroy his ship?
好像是那样的
Sounds vaguely familiar.
现在你却想要我违反规定，把他放走？
And now you want me to go against protocol and let him go.
其实，不是他我们活不到现在。了解
- Well, he is the reason we're alive.
- I realize that, Colonel.
也是他把你置于危险之中的
He's also the reason you were in danger,
更不用说这会带来多严重的安全隐患
not to mention an incredible security risk.
好吧，你看，反正他都要死了
All right, look, he's probably gonna die anyway.
要是他能活下来呢？他会记起来他都干了些什么
- And if he survives?
- He's gonna remember what we did.
无论你喜欢与否，他都是我们对抗幽灵的最佳同盟
Like it or not, he's our best ally in the fight against the Wraith.
如果我们想传播我们的基因疗法
If we ever get around to perfecting this gene therapy,
我们肯定需要他来帮忙分发
we're gonna need his help to deploy it.
你知道做这种决定简直是拿我的事业来赌
You realize this is the kind of decision that could cost me my job.
难道一直以来不是吗？
Well, aren't they all?
很感谢你放我走
I appreciate your decision to let me go.
说话要算数的
A deal's a deal.
我会记住这一切，John Sheppard
I will remember this, John Sheppard.